<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Guides on Horizon</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/go-horizon/guides/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Guides on Horizon</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 May 2015 08:00:59 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/go-horizon/guides/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/go-horizon/guides/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2015 08:00:59 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/go-horizon/guides/intro/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Horizon is the client facing API server for the Stellar ecosystem.  See &lt;a href=&#34;TODO&#34;&gt;an overview of the Stellar ecosystem&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Horizon provides three significant portions of functionality:  The Transactions API, the History API, and the Trading API.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;transactions-api:34c4da6d4768d05e50db99357a299b5c&#34;&gt;Transactions API&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Transactions API exists to help you make transactions against the Stellar network.  It provides ways to help you create valid transactions, such as providing an account&amp;rsquo;s sequence number or latest known balances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the read endpoints, the Transactions API also provides the endpoint to submit transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;history-api:34c4da6d4768d05e50db99357a299b5c&#34;&gt;History API&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The History API provides endpoints for retrieving data about what has happened in the past on the Stellar network.  It provides (or will provide) endpoints that let you:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Retrieve transaction details&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Load transactions that effect a given account&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Load payment history for an account&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Load trade history for a given order book&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;trading-api:34c4da6d4768d05e50db99357a299b5c&#34;&gt;Trading API&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;api-overview:34c4da6d4768d05e50db99357a299b5c&#34;&gt;API Overview&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following section describes a couple of important concepts for the Horizon API at a high level.  Understanding these concepts will help make your overall experience integrating with Horizon much easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;response-format:34c4da6d4768d05e50db99357a299b5c&#34;&gt;Response Format&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than using a fully custom way of representing the resources we expose in Horizon, we use &lt;a href=&#34;http://stateless.co/hal_specification.html&#34;&gt;HAL&lt;/a&gt;. HAL is a hypermedia format in JSON that remains simple while giving us a couple of benefits such as simpler client integration for several languages. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mikekelly/hal_specification/wiki/Libraries&#34;&gt;this wiki page&lt;/a&gt; for a list of libraries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;responses.md&#34;&gt;Responses&lt;/a&gt; for more details&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;error-format:34c4da6d4768d05e50db99357a299b5c&#34;&gt;Error Format&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HAL doesn&amp;rsquo;t really have any special consideration for error responses.  To provide some standardization to our API&amp;rsquo;s error messages we use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://tools.ietf.org/html/draft-ietf-appsawg-http-problem-00&#34;&gt;Problem Details for HTTP APIs RFC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;errors.md&#34;&gt;errors&lt;/a&gt; for more details&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;paging:34c4da6d4768d05e50db99357a299b5c&#34;&gt;Paging&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some resources in Horizon represent a collection of other resources.  Almost always, loading this collection in its entirety is not feasible.  To work around this, we provide a way to page through a collection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The paging system in Horizon is known as a &lt;em&gt;token-based&lt;/em&gt; paging system.  There is no &amp;ldquo;page 3&amp;rdquo; or the like.  Paging through a collection in a token-based paging system involves three pieces of data:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the &lt;em&gt;paging token&lt;/em&gt;, which is an opaque value that logically represents the last record seen by a client.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the &lt;em&gt;limit&lt;/em&gt;, or page size, a positive integer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the &lt;em&gt;order&lt;/em&gt; applied to the whole collection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;paging.md&#34;&gt;paging&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;api-reference:34c4da6d4768d05e50db99357a299b5c&#34;&gt;API Reference&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Horizon is lightly self-documenting through use of hyperlinks in responses (such that you should be able to navigate through the dataset without too much trouble), we also have reference documentation available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We document our API using &lt;a href=&#34;https://apiblueprint.org/&#34;&gt;API Blueprint&lt;/a&gt;, and you can see the raw file &lt;a href=&#34;horizon.apib&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We host the documentation for our API presently with apiary.  You can find this documentation at (&lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.stellarhorizon.apiary.io/&#34;&gt;http://docs.stellarhorizon.apiary.io/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>problems</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/go-horizon/guides/problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2015 15:48:17 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/go-horizon/guides/problems/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>